myfreearticle.com 2011-11-02

# Privacy Policy .:. Free Articles

## [Privacy Policy](http://www.myfreearticle.com/privacy-policy "Privacy Policy")

**MyFreeArticle.com** has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for **MyFreeArticle.com**.

### Information Automatically Logged

**MyFreeArticle.com** makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP Addresses), type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track userâ€™s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.  
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information.

### Cookies and Web Beacons

**MyFreeArticle.com** does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.  
This site uses cookies to keep track of any activities, and to make sure you donâ€™t see the same ad repeatedly. We also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so you donâ€™t have to re-enter it each time you visit this site.

### Advertisement

**MyFreeArticle.com** has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. **MyFreeArticle.com** â€™s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.  
If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsersâ€™ respective websites.  
We use an outside ad company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Web site, cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information.

### Registration Forms

Our siteâ€™s registration form requires users to give us contact information (like their name, email, and postal address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level).

Contact information from the registration forms is used to send information about our company, and to send promotional material from some of our partners to our customers. The customerâ€™s contact information is also used to get in touch with the customer when necessary.

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site.  
We use this data to tailor our visitorâ€™s experience at our site showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences.

### Order Forms

Our site may, in some cases, use an order form for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect contact information (like their email address), and financial information (like their account or credit card numbers).

Contact information from the order forms is used to ship purchases, information about our company, and to send promotional material from some of our partners to our customers. The customerâ€™s contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary.

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings, see the choice/opt-out section below.

Financial information that is collected is used to check the usersâ€™ qualifications for registration, to bill the user for products and services.

### Surveys

We will occassionally run surveys where user information is collected.

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like email address) and demographic information (like zip code, age, or income level).

Contact information from the surveys is used to ship purchases, information about our company. The customerâ€™s contact information is also used to send promotional material from some of our partners to our customers, and to get in touch with the visitor when necessary.

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

Unique identifiers (such as social security numbers) are collected from Web site visitors to verify the userâ€™s identity, for use as account numbers in our record system.

Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site.  
We use this data to tailor our visitorâ€™s experience at our site showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences.

### Contests

We may, on certain occassions, run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (like email address).

Contact information from the contests is used to ship purchases, information about our company, and to send promotional material from some of our partners to our customers. The customerâ€™s contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary.

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

### External Links

This site contains links to other sites, **MyFreeArticle.com** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

### Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. These security measures include password protected directories through the use of .htaccess files and customized cgi programs to prevent access to specific areas of the web site.

### Childrenâ€™s Guidelines

We care about children and understand that they have special privacy needs. Therefore, we have adopted the following privacy policy regarding children:

  1. We will NOT collect, use, or distribute to third parties personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent.
  2. We will NOT give the child access to unmonitored chat rooms, message boards, email accounts, or other services that would give the child the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent
  3. When verifiable parental consent is not obtained, we will only use the online contact information (such as email) to: 
    1. Respond directly to the childâ€™s request on a one-time basis and not use that information to re-contact the child for other purposes.
    2. Request the name or online contact information of a parent for the purpose of obtaining verifiable parental consent or providing parental notification.
    3. Respond more than once directly to a specific request from a child (such as in the case where a child requests a newsletter subscription) and not used to re-contact the child for other purposes. We will use our best efforts to provide parental notification, which will include the nature and intended use as well as an opportunity for the parent to prevent the use of the information and participation in the activity.
  4. We will NOT entice the child to divulge more information than is needed to participate in any activity, game, or service.
  5. We will provide the parent a description of the specific types of a personally identifiable information collected from their child upon request. We will allow the parent to refuse further use or future online collection of personally identifiable information and provide a way for a parent to obtain any personally identifiable information collected from their child.
  6. We will provide notice to children in age appropriate terms of what personally identifiable information is to be collected.
  7. We will NOT provide any links to Web sites that are unsuitable for children.
  8. We will encourage children to get their parentâ€™s permission before sharing personal information online.

### Choice/Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving promotional/marketing information from our partners, and us.

### Data Quality/Access

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

### Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact: admin[at]myfreearticle.com.

## [Seven Deadly Sins of Work Life Balance](http://www.myfreearticle.com/seven-deadly-sins-of-work-life-balance.html "Seven Deadly Sins of Work Life Balance")

In the thirteenth century, Dante listed the Seven Deadly Sins on the pathway to Paradise: Gluttony, lust, greed, envy, pride, ...

## [Coffee Cupping For The Fun Of It](http://www.myfreearticle.com/coffee-cupping-for-the-fun-of-it.html "Coffee Cupping For The Fun Of It")

Having a coffee cupping party at home is a great way to socialize and enjoy coffee while evaluating and sharing ...

## [Mombasa & the Kenyan Coast – Where the Sun is Ever Faithful](http://www.myfreearticle.com/mombasa-the-kenyan-coast-where-the-sun-is-ever-faithful.html "Mombasa & the Kenyan Coast – Where the Sun is Ever Faithful")

For the tourist, the Kenyan coast can be seen as five regions. These are: the town and island of Mombasa; ...

## [The Budget 2005 & Inheritance Tax: Has the Chancellor Done Enough?](http://www.myfreearticle.com/the-budget-2005-inheritance-tax-has-the-chancellor-done-enough.html "The Budget 2005 & Inheritance Tax: Has the Chancellor Done Enough?")

Introduction The Government's economic objective is to build a strong economy and a fair society, where there is opportunity and security ...

## [How To Change a Tire Without Help](http://www.myfreearticle.com/how-to-change-a-tire-without-help.html "How To Change a Tire Without Help")

In order to change a tire you should make sure you have parked your car at the side of the ...
